all right this is my story
the part of my story that's about my
neurodiversity which for me encompasses
three main things my EDD my autism and
my brain damage which I called my brain
change I have known I've had a TD my
whole life and I've dealt with it I got
through high school with high grades I
went to university and graduated because
part of a DD is kind of waiting for this
adrenaline to kick in and then being
able for me anyway and then being able
to put all this information in my head
and complex logical systems seem to
stick more easily but I was never able
to study to sit and actually like force
information in if it wasn't already
there to be I could I could that's not
true I could memorize things but for
very short periods of time so I've
memorized the countries of the world but
they wouldn't stick you know they'd just
be there for the test then I had my
brain change which wasn't a switch it
wasn't one day I was one way in one day
another way it's still changing it's
ever-changing
it started happening after my first
surgery when my brain swelled and then
after the radiation it I there's was a
more definite change and so I went from
being able to put in information from
feeling like my job in the world was to
learn everything so I could save the
world I had to go through a big period
of depression because I was no longer
able to do that I couldn't learn I
couldn't I could take a course not pay
much attention and ace it before because
might not pay much attention was paying
attention with my EDD was like I'd be
doing like doodlee and her playing card
games on the computer while everyone
else was listening and I would ace the
test to not be able to use adrenaline
because it's poison for people with
chronic fatigue syndrome and not knowing
how to put new information in without it
not being able to concentrate on on
words words would like it just took way
too much energy to read and and then
autism which both
my whole life looking back but the
difference of my a DD which I've known
I've had my whole life and it's part of
my childhood through adolescence
identity and it didn't really I figured
how to work with it so didn't really get
in the way versus figuring out I had
autism at the age of 39 and being like
oh that's what all of that was being
able to look back with retrospect and
see that piece of the difference is and
I didn't mention this in my autism video
that one of the main reasons I did also
figure it out autism was that my child
to me looks very neurodiverse but yet
isn't she actually probably cause a DD
like everybody else in my family but she
doesn't have autism like she is she is a
huge extrovert can read people's
emotions can like the things she puts
together I'm like oh so there was
something she had that I had that she
didn't and as well as these brain
changes this neurological thing that
happens like I no longer my memory isn't
as good as it was I can't recall words I
counted call people which was always
kind of a problem there like face
blindness which i think is a is a common
trait in you know assist sick people as
well and I've had that my whole life I
would get people confused in my class if
I have it really a really hard time
unfortunately with them people that are
a different race than me being able to
tell them apart and I know that to
society makes you appear racist but it's
also sorry my brain doesn't do it its
facial blindness like I can't control
what I can't control I can apologize for
it I can try to make amends for it I can
explain it but I can't control it and
but I feel like everything that I have
it's part of my story but it's exactly
what I was supposed to experience to do
what I'm here to do if I had always been
if it was just a TD and I want ISM and
I'd always been the same way it I'd have
all of these same prejudices of like
propping up people that are intelligent
like you two could be at elegent what a
horrible trait to not be intelligent now
we look at intelligence like I look at
looks like yeah life is easier if you if
you look nice to a point life is easier
if you're in some
to a point it's actually I think this
dislike show the opposite of that but
like if you're if you're the opposite of
intelligent then it's definitely harder
I can't get a job if your IQ is very low
it's very very hard to get a job keep a
job get relationships keep relationships
and so I've experienced two very
distinct brains in fact I experienced
them sometimes in the same day my brain
is never gonna go back to where it was
where I can I don't think but I can
input all this external information and
feel like I can learn physics and
chemistry and biology and economics and
and geography and world events all to
like save the world but if it hadn't
changed I wouldn't have had to sit with
the knowledge I already knew and revamp
it to figure out how we can create a
world that works for everyone if I
hadn't had this experience of having
both a brilliant mind and then in many
areas away less than brilliant mind I
wouldn't have the compassion
understanding for that right this is not
your intelligence is a gift you can't
look down on other people who don't have
it because they just don't have it like
they their brain connections don't work
the same as yours and some of those
brain connections we label its
intelligence and some of them we label
as non intelligence and there are
different types of intelligence and most
people aren't all of them so there's
ones that again we value more than
others but all of them are valuable and
it's your combination of intelligence
that makes you both valuable even if
you're low on all of them or high on all
of them it's the combination of what you
bring to the table that makes our
neurodiversity the key that is going to
help us save this planet and create a
world of abundance and connection that
works for everyone